# YOONJOO LEE

## yoonjoo.lee@kaist.ac,kr | yoonjoolee.com

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI), natural language processing (NLP), and Education. I aim to support people to learn from and understand information-dense text (e.g., lecture transcript, scientific article) by structuring the information in the context to create conversational questions and answers to scaffold people's understanding.

#### **EDUCATION**

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim Sep. 2020 – Present

**Ewha Womans University** 

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics

Graduated with Honors (Magna Cum Laude)

University of California, Davis

Exchange student in Mathematics

Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

Seoul, Republic of Korea Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020

> **Davis, CA, USA** Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **Conference and Journal Papers**

[C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

[C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create Effective Studying Environments

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral Efficiency

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

[C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

Last Updated: April 20, 2023

#### **Posters and Workshop Papers**

# [P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

## [P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

#### [P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, Yoonjoo Lee, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters

### [P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# [P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab

Nov. 2022 – March. 2023

- Designed a schema for questions triggered from academic paper by adapting prior literature in education to a paper reading context.
- Collected various advanced questions based on the proposed schema from academic paper readers [under submission].

KIXLAB, KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern

Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

• Investigated user experiences with VR services by analyzing large-scale text data using various techniques like clustering, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis.

## **Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)**

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group

• Performed analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE with probabilistic modeling and Deep Neural Networks. [P1, C1, C2]

• Participated in research about predicting future Resource Block Usage by applying stochastic modeling and Recurrent Neural Networks. [P2]

Undergraduate Research Intern, Data Sciences Group

Jan. 2018 – Feb. 2018

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019

• Devised a module for pre-processing and summarizing mobile traffic data in Python.

### **TEACHING**

#### **Introduction to Social Computing**

Fall 2020, Fall 2021

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Time Series Analysis Spring 2019

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

Last Updated: April 20, 2023

## **SERVICES**

## **Program Committee**

• CHI LBW 2023

#### Reviewer

- CHI 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

## **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2022

KAIST-Google ExploreCSR Student Organizer	2022 – Present
Programming Mentoring Leader of Student Organizer	2016 – 2017
Mathematics Mentoring in Ewha Girls High School  Mentor	2015 – 2017

# HONORS, AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

HUNURS, AWARDS AND SCHULARSHIPS	
Research Assistant Scholarship College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University	2019
Admission Scholarship College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University	2018
Honors Scholarship College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2014, 2015, 2016, 2017
Dean's List College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

# Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

2017